Robert Francis Papers
Robert Francis Papers
1926-1967
Francis, Robert, 1901-1987.
5.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, author. Correspondence (1926-1966) with Robert Frost, John Holmes, Theodore Morrison, and others; writings (1936-1967) include typescript poems, essays, and book manuscripts; and printed material, including articles and poems.
148987
Biographical History
Robert Francis (1901-1987) was an American poet and author. Born in Upland, Pennsylvania in 1901, the son of Ebenezer Francis, a minister, his childhood was spent in towns in New Jersey and New York states until 1910, when the family moved to Massachusetts. Francis graduated from Harvard College (B.A., 1923) and then taught in the preparatory school of the American University of Beirut, Lebanon, for a year. He returned to attend Harvard University, where he received an Ed. M., followed by a year of teaching high school English in Amherst (1926).
Francis began writing "with a view to publication" about the time he moved to Amherst. By living economically and by doing all his own chores, he has been able to live without salaried positions and to devote much of his time to writing. He held occasional positions as a violin teacher, as an English teacher at Mount Holyoke College, and as a teacher at summer writers' conferences. In 1940, Francis moved alone in a one-man house called Fort Juniper, in Amherst, Massachusetts and subsequently adopted the juniper as his "coat-of- arms."
Francis received numerous awards over his career, including the Shelly Memorial Award and the Golden Rose of the New England Poetry Club. He held fellowships at the Bread Loaf Writers' Conference and in Rome from the American Academy of Arts and Letters. His poems have appeared in Saturday Review, The New Yorker, Forum, Yankee, and other national literary magazines. His prose works include We Fly Away (1948), The Satirical Rogue on Poetry (1968), and The Trouble With Francis (1971). His six volumes of poetry include Come Out Into the Sun (1965), The Orb Weaver (1960), The Face Against the Glass (1950), The Sound I Listened For (1943, 1944), Valhalla and Other Poems (1938), and Stand With Me Here (1936). Other works include Rome Without Camera (1958) and What a Witch Told Me (1956).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Francis Papers contain biographical material, correspondence, writings, and recordings. Notices of awards for Mr. Francis's poetry, published material about personal appearances, biographical material, 1939-1967.
Correspondence, 1926-1966, comprised of exchanges between Mr. Francis and his fellow-writers, includes both incoming and outgoing. Here are letters to critics, words of congratulation and criticism about Mr. Francis's books of poetry, and personal letters between friends. Important correspondents include American Academy of Arts and Letters, Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards, Gerald Warner Brace, Robert Frost, John Holmes, Houghton Mifflin Company, Amy Lowell Poetry Traveling Scholarship, The Massachusetts Review, Theodore Morrison, David Morton, New England Poetry Club, and Mary P. Sears Trust.
Writings, 1936-1967, consist of notes, original typescripts of individual poems, printed versions of the poems, book reviews, essays, non-fiction, poetry, and one item about Francis. Most of the writings are worksheets of poems revised by the author; also included are printed versions of some of the poem and notes about the revisions and publication of the poems. Essays, 1940-1953, consist of newspaper clippings taken from the "Home Forum Page" of the Christian Science Monitor, including fan mail about particular essays. A list of this correspondence, with dates, may be found in the first folder in Box 1. Non-fiction includes articles printed about literary subjects, 1963-1967. Poetry, 1947-1966, contains an alphabetical listing of poems, either in typescript or printed form, which were not included in any of Mr. Francis's volumes.
Published material contains issues of Forum and a copy of the Official Register of Harvard University, vol. XLII, no. 2. Three Tape recordings are of Mr. Francis reading his own poetry.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is subdivided into incoming and outgoing, each arranged alphabetically. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type and within that by title; writings about Francis appear at the end of this series. Most of the writings are worksheets of poems revised by the author; these are arranged alphabetically under the title of the book in which the poems appeared, as are printed versions of some of the poems. Notes about the revisions and publication of the poems are filed with the poem, though in some cases these notes were grouped together and called "Histories" by the author. Published material is arranged alphabetically. The oversize package of tape recordings is in no particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Francis, Robert, 1901-1987 -- Archives.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Holmes, John Clellon, 1926-; Morrison, Theodore, 1901-; American poetry -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Poets, American.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Essays.; Manuscripts for publication.; Poems.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert Francis, 1968 and 1969.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Correspondence, 24 Aug.-14 Nov. 1960, undated; includes published material from 1960 and undated (Box 1)
  - Awards, 28 Feb. 1939-18 Mar. 1967; includes published material from 1955 and 1957 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming "from fellow-writers", 13 July 1936-13 June 1966; undated
    - Adams, Raymond (Box 1)
    - Baird, Theodore (Box 1)
    - Baker, Ray Stannard (Box 1)
    - Bingham, Millicent (Box 1)
    - Brace, Gerald Warner (Box 1)
    - Bynner, Witter (Box 1)
    - Carrier, Constance (Box 1)
    - Dickey, James (Box 1)
    - Dike, Donald (Box 1)
    - Eberhart, Richard (Box 1)
    - Fowler, Helen (Box 1)
    - Frost, Robert (photocopy) (Box 1)
    - Garrett, George (Box 1)
    - Graves, W. L. (Box 1)
    - Hall, Donald (Box 1)
    - Hamburger, Michael (Box 1)
    - Harding, Walter (Box 1)
    - Hayford, James (Box 1)
    - Hicks, John H. (Box 1)
    - Holmes, John (Box 1)
    - Houpt, C. Theodore (Box 1)
    - Jackson, David (Box 1)
    - Meredith, William (Box 1)
    - Merrill, James (Box 1)
    - Moore, Robert Thomas (Box 1)
    - Morrison, Theodore (Box 1)
    - Morse, Samuel French (Box 1)
    - Morton, David (Box 1)
    - Norvig, Gerda (Box 1)
    - Schacht, Marshall (Box 1)
    - Starbuck, George (Box 1)
    - Stewart, Albert (Box 1)
    - Still, James (Box 1)
    - Stocking, Marion K. (Box 1)
    - Summers, Hollis (Box 1)
    - Sweeney, John L. (Box 1)
    - Van Doren, Mark (Box 1)
    - Wallace, Robert (Box 1)
    - Whicher, George Frisbie (Box 1)
  - Outgoing, "most to fellow-writers"
    - 13 July 1926-13 June 1966, undated, includes published material (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Address: New England: Anthology An Expression in Poetry, [1954]; original typescript and published material (Box 1)
  - "Check list of reviews of all books except The Satirical Rogue", undated; original typescript annotated (Box 1)
  - Bibliography
    - "Robert Francis: A Bibliography", undated; original typescript (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Come Out Into the Sun
      - Worksheets of poems
        - "Ambush", 7 June 1962 (Box 1)
        - "Aphrodite", 8 Mar. 1962 (Box 1)
        - "The Articles of War", undated; original typescripts revised, notes (Box 1)
        - "Astronomer", undated; original typescripts revised, notes (Box 1)
        - "The Black Hood", undated; notes (Box 1)
        - "Coin Diver, 10 July 1961 (Box 1)
        - "Condor", undated (Box 1)
        - "Dolphin", 22 Oct. 1961 (Box 1)
        - "Edith Sitwell", 21 Mar. 1961 (Box 1)
        - "Enviable (Observation)", 19 Nov. 1960; original typescripts revised (Box 1)
        - "The Forced Forsythia", 7 Jan. 1960 (Box 1)
        - "He Is The Boy", 27 Feb. 1956 (Box 1)
        - "Icicles", undated (Box 1)
        - "Idyll of Lake Reedy", 14 Aug. 1964 (Box 1)
        - "Metal and Mettle", 1 Apr. 1964 (Box 1)
        - "My Teachers Are the Centripetal Ones", undated (Box 1)
        - "Old Man's Confession of Faith", 29 Jan. 1963 (Box 1)
        - "Old Men", undated (Box 1)
        - "The Packing Case", 29 Nov. 1960 (Box 1)
        - "Skier", undated (Box 1)
        - "Sniper", [Sept. 1960] (Box 1)
        - "Thoreau in Italy", undated (Box 1)
        - "Time and the Sergeant", undated (Box 1)
        - "Watching Gymnasts", undated (Box 1)
      - "These magazines contain first appearances of the poems later collected in the first section..."
        - "The Articles of War," "The Eagle Plain" in The Massachusetts Review, vol. 6, no. 4 ( Autumn, 1965), pp. 690-691. (Box 2)
        - "The Black Hood" in Harvard Alumni Bulletin, vol. 62, no. 17 ( 2 July 1960), pp. /4u. (Box 2)
        - "Come", "Emergence" in Commonweal, vol. 81, no. 19 ( 5 Feb. 1965), p. 605. (Box 2)
        - "Eagle" in Kentucky Writing, no. 3 ( 1960), p. 11. (Box 2)
        - "The Forced Forsythia" in The Lyric, vol. 41, no. 2 ( Spring, 1961), p. 31. (Box 2)
        - "Hallelujah: A Sestina," untitled, c. 1959 (Box 2)
        - "In Memoriam: Four Poets" news clipping, untitled, 6 Mar. 1965 (Box 2)
        - "Old Men" in Commonweal, vol. 82, no. 15 ( 2 July 1965), p. 468 (Box 2)
        - "Stellaria" in The Massachusetts Review, vol. 3, no. 1. (Autumn, 1961), p. 35. (Box 2)
        - "Thoreau in Italy", "Sniper", "Cinna", "Edith Sitwell Assumes the Role of Luna of If you Know What I Mean Said the Moon," "The Packing Case", "Dolphin", "Observation", "Coin Diver" in the Massachusetts Review, vol. 3, no. 3 ( Spring, 1962), pp. 475-480. (Box 2)
        - "Watching Gymnasts" in Syracuse 10, vol. 3, no. 3 ( Mar., 1961), p. 7. (Box 2)
    - The Face Against the Glass
      - Worksheets of poems
        - "Amanita", published material, undated (Box 2)
        - "Babylon and Babel", 13-14 Aug. 1944; undated (Box 2)
        - "The Big Tent", May 1948; undated; includes published material (Box 2)
        - "The Buzz Plane", 3 Sep. 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "The Dandelion Gatherer", 4 Mar. 1950 (Box 2)
        - "The Faultless Dead", 7 Aug. 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "Fortune", undated (Box 2)
        - "Gloria", 20 Dec. 1948; undated (Box 2)
        - "The Heiress", 9 June 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "Here by the Sea", 1947-1950 (Box 2)
        - "Museum Birds", 10 Sept. 1945 (Box 2)
        - "Oh World of Toms", 1948; undated (Box 2)
        - "Part for the Whole", 1 Feb. 1945; undated (Box 2)
        - "Peace", 8 May 1946; undated (Box 2)
        - "Portrait", 9 June 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "The Spy", 27 Oct. 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "Strewing Herbs", 2 May 1948; undated (Box 2)
        - "Superior Vantage", 15 July 1948; undated (Box 2)
        - "Thistle Seed in the Wind", 28 Oct. 1947; undated (Box 2)
        - "Two Words", undated (Box 2)
        - "Weathervane", 3 Mar. 1948; undated (Box 2)
      - "First appearances of some poems later collected in ..."
        - "The Big Tent," "Portrait" in Poetry, vol. 73, no. 2 ( Nov. 1948), pp. 84-85. (Box 2)
        - "Here by the Sea" in The New Yorker, vol. 24, no. 19 ( 3 July 1948), p. 57. (Box 2)
        - "Superior Vantage" in The New Yorker, vol. 26, no. 19 ( 1 July 1950), p. 27-- (Box 2)
        - "Two Words", "His Wealth", "Fortune", "The Oxen", "The Hawk", in Poetry, vol. 63, no. 5 ( Aug., 1946), pp. 246-248. (Box 2)
        - [vol. 1], c. 1950 (Box 2)
    - The Orb Weaver
      - "precursors of poems in" (worksheets)
        - "Eagle", undated (Box 3)
        - "Poison Ivy", undated (Box 3)
        - "Sun", undated (Box 3)
      - Worksheets of poems
        - "The Aloof Peak", 22 Oct. 1954 (Box 3)
        - "Beyond Biology", 6 Mar. 1951 (Box 3)
        - "Boy Riding Forward Backward", [Spring, 1955] (Box 3)
        - "Burial", [22-28 Jan. 1955] (Box 3)
        - "Catch", [13-14 Jan. 1950] (Box 3)
        - "Come Out Into the Sun", [1955] (Box 3)
        - "Confession", undated (Box 3)
        - "Demonstration", 1 Aug. 1950 (Box 3)
        - "Desiring to Give All", 18 Aug. 1946 (Box 3)
        - "Dog Day Night", 8 Aug. 1947 (Box 3)
        - "Dry Point", 7 Jan. 1952 (Box 3)
        - "The Eagle in Retreat" ("The Retiring Eagle"), undated (Box 3)
        - "Epitaph" (Box 3)
        - "Farm Boy After Summer", 22 July 1953 (Box 3)
        - "High Diver", 26 June 1952 (Box 3)
        - "Monadnock", 1 May 1948 (Box 3)
        - "Remind Me of Apples", 6 Aug. 1947 (Box 3)
        - "The Revelers", undated [1955] (Box 3)
        - "The Rock Climbers", 28 Aug. 1957 (Box 3)
        - "Sailboat, Your Secret", undated (Box 3)
        - "Squash in Blossom", 17 July 1950 (Box 3)
        - "Three Darks Come Down Together", 6 Oct. 1955 (Box 3)
        - "With the Year's Cooling", 16 Sep. 1952 (Box 3)
      - "...magazines in which 20 of the poems in the Orb Weaver first appeared." undated
        - "Boy Riding Forward Backward" in Saturday Review, vol. 39, no.10 ( Mar. 10, 1956), p 13 (Box 3)
        - "Colo" in Poetry, vol. 84, no. 5 ( Aug. 1954), p. 271. (Box 3)
        - "Come Out Into the Sun" in The New Yorker, vol. 31, no. 7 ( Apr. 2, 1955). p. 40. (Box 3)
        - "Desiring to Give All" in Forum, vol. 107, no. 5 ( May, 1947), p. 457. (Box 3)
        - "Dog Day Night" in Yankee, vol. 14, no.10 ( Oct. 1950), p. 74. (Box 3)
        - "Encounter", Part for the Whole" in Poetry, vol. 66, no. 3 ( June, 1945), pp. 126-127 (Box 3)
        - "Exclusive Blue" in Saturday Review, vol. 36, no. 12 ( Mar. 21, 1953). p.22. (Box 3)
        - "The Faultless Dead"," The Base-Stealer" in Forum, vol. 109, no. 6 ( June, 1948), p. 346. (Box 3)
        - "Gold" in The New England Galaxy, vol. 1, no. 2 ( Fall, 1959), pp. 16-17 (Box 3)
        - "Hide-and-Seek" in Voices, no. 127 ( Autumn, 1946), p. 33. (Box 3)
        - "My Teachers are the Centripetal Ones", "Past Tense", in The Lyric, vol. 33, no. 3 ( Summer, 1953), p. 208. (Box 3)
        - "The Orb Weaver" in Forum, vol. 105, no. 2 ( Feb, 1946), p. 525. (Box 3)
        - "Remind Me of Apples" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, vol. 24, no. 4 ( Autumn, 1948), p. 557. (Box 3)
        - "The Revelers" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, vol. 32, no. 3 ( Summer, 1956), pp. 376-379. (Box 3)
        - "Sailboat, Your Secret" in Poetry, vol. 86, no. 4 ( July, 1955), p. 233. (Box 3)
        - "The Seed-Eaters" in Saturday Review, vol. 36, no.14 ( Apr. 3, 1954), p. 22. (Box 3)
        - "The Strewing Herbs", "Monadnock", "Geology", "Glass", "Two Figures" in The Lyric, vol. 28, no. 4 ( Winter, 1949), pp. 146-148. (Box 3)
        - "Swimmer" in Saturday Review, vol. 36, no. 28 ( July 11, 1953), p.14. (Box 3)
        - "With the Year's Cooling" in Saturday Review, vol. 36, no. 42 ( Oct. 17, 1953), p. 24 (Box 3)
        - "Histories of all poems in", undated (Box 4)
      - Book reviews, book jacket, 1960-1961; 1966-1967,; undated; published material (Box 4)
    - The Sound I Listened For
      - "Precursors of poems in"
        - "Flower and Bee, undated (Box 4)
        - "The Mouse", undated (Box 4)
        - "October Summer", undated (Box 4)
      - Worksheets
        - "Dedication Poem", undated [Dec., 1942?] (Box 4)
        - "Afternoon Drive", holographs revised, undated (Box 4)
        - "Altitude", undated [6-10 Mar. 1940] (Box 4)
        - "Answer", undated [11-26 Sep. 1941] (Box 4)
        - "April Thunder", undated (Box 4)
        - "As Easily as Trees", undated (Box 4)
        - "Bluejays", undated [late summer or early autumn, 1942] (Box 4)
        - "Boy Sleeping", undated (Box 4)
        - "Clairvoyance", undated (Box 4)
        - "Distance and Peace", undated (Box 4)
        - "Evening Ride", holographs, undated (Box 4)
        - "Excellence", undated (Box 4)
        - "Fair and Unfair", undated (Box 4)
        - "Five Silver Foxes", undated [1943] (Box 4)
        - "Flower and Bee", undated [1943] (Box 4)
        - "The Four", undated (Box 4)
        - "Fruit", undated (Box 4)
        - "The Goldfish Bowl", undated (Box 4)
        - "Good Night Near Christmas", undated (Box 4)
        - "His Own"], [1943] (Box 4)
        - "If We Had Known", undated (Box 4)
        - "Indoor Lady", undated (Box 4)
        - "Interrupted Fern", undated (Box 4)
        - "It May Not Comfort You", undated (Box 4)
        - "The Laughers", undated (Box 4)
        - "Nothing is Far", undated (Box 4)
        - "Now That Your Shoulders Reach My Shoulders", undated (Box 4)
        - "Old Man Feeding Hens", undated [spring or summer of 1943] (Box 4)
        - "The Old of the Moon in August", undated (Box 4)
        - "Old Roofs", undated (Box 4)
        - "On That Cool Plane", holographs [, undated [22 Aug.-14 Sept. 1943] (Box 4)
        - "Past and Future", undated [1937?] (Box 4)
        - "Poverty Grass", undated [Summer, 1943] (Box 4)
        - "Preparation", undated [Feb. 1939] (Box 4)
        - "The Reading of the Psalm", undated [1941] (Box 4)
        - "Rocking Boulder", undated [1943] (Box 4)
        - "Salt", undated (Box 4)
        - "Serpent as Vine", undated [29 Aug. 1943] (Box 4)
        - "Shadows", undated (Box 4)
        - "Sight", undated (Box 4)
        - "Sing a Song Of Juniper", undated [18 Nov. 1941] (Box 4)
        - "Socrates and the Crowd", holographs, undated (Box 4)
        - "The Sound I Listened For", undated (Box 4)
        - "Statement", undated (Box 4)
        - "Summons", undated (Box 4)
        - "The Thief", undated (Box 4)
        - "Two Glories", undated (Box 4)
        - "Unanimity", undated (Box 4)
        - "The Wasp", undated (Box 4)
        - "What Has To Be", undated (Box 4)
        - "While Sunday Morning", undated (Box 4)
        - "Who Comes As Light", undated (Box 4)
        - "Willow Woman", undated (Box 4)
        - "Winter", undated (Box 4)
        - Notes original typescripts, undated (Box 5)
      - "First appearances of some poems later collected in", published material
        - "Answer" in The Catholic World, vol. 150, no. 944 ( Nov., 1943), p. 171. (Box 5)
        - "Evening Ride" in Poetry, vol. 56, no. 5 ( Aug., 1940), p. 253. (Box 5)
        - "The Laughers" in The Lyric, vol. 23, no. 4 ( Winter, 1944), p. 93. (Box 5)
        - "Perspective" in Voices, no. 112 ( Winter, 1943), p16. (Box 5)
        - "Poems for James Harker" in Voices, no. 107 ( Autumn, 1941), pp. 23-25. (Box 5)
        - "Statement" in Poetry, vol. 55, no. 2 ( May, 1942), p. 64. (Box 5)
        - "Winter" in The Lyric, vol. 20, no.3 ( Autumn, 1940), p. 89. (Box 5)
      - [vols. 2 and 3], c. 1943; c. 1944
        - "Histories of all poems in ... ", undated (Box 5)
        - Book reviews, 20 June 1943-Winter, 1945; published material (Box 5)
    - Stand With Me Here
      - Worksheets
        - "Apple Gatherers", undated (Box 5)
        - "Days", undated (Box 5)
        - "Dirge", undated (Box 5)
        - "Diver", undated (Box 5)
        - "Earthworm", undated (Box 5)
        - "Fall", undated (Box 5)
        - "February Snow", undated (Box 5)
        - "Firewarden on Kearsarge", undated (Box 5)
        - "Gargoyle (First Sister)", undated (Box 5)
        - "Grotesque (Second Sister)", undated (Box 5)
        - "Iron Effigy (Third Sister)", undated (Box 5)
        - "Hay", undated (Box 5)
        - "The Hound", undated (Box 5)
        - "Legend of Orient Point", undated (Box 5)
        - "Pitch Pine", undated (Box 5)
        - "Portraits", undated (Box 5)
        - "Prophet", undated (Box 5)
        - "Soldierhood", undated (Box 5)
      - "First appearances of some poems later collected in" published material
        - "A Boy's November", in The Target, vol. 96, no. 45 ( 7 Nov. 1936), p. 2. (Box 5)
        - "Comet" in Christian Science Monitor ( 2 Sept. 1930), p. 8. (Box 5)
        - "Homeward", "Mountain Blueberries", "Artist", "Prophet", "Identity", Before", Pitch Pine" in The Lyric, vol. 16, no. 2 ( Summer, 1936), pp. 19-21. (Box 5)
        - "The Hound" in Harper's Magazine, no. 1036 ( Sept., 1936) p. 385. (Box 5)
        - "Iron Effigy" in Voices, no. 66 ( Oct.- Nov., 1932), pp. 29-31. (Box 5)
        - "Night Train" in Christian Science Monitor ( 7 Aug. 1936), p. 8. (Box 5)
        - "Roots" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, vol. 10, no. 4 ( Oct., 1934), p. 558. (Box 5)
      - Book reviews, 16 Sept. 1936-Winter 1937; undated; published material (Box 5)
    - Valhalla
      - "First appearance of some poems later collected in"
        - "Balance" in Christian Science Monitor ( 15 Aug. 1938), p. 12. (Box 5)
        - "Blue Winter" in Christian Science Monitor ( 15 Sept. 1936), p. 7. (Box 5)
        - "Bonfire on the Snow" in New York Times ( 7 Sept. 1938), p. 24. (Box 5)
        - "Dwight" in New York Times ( 17 May 1938), p. 22. (Box 5)
        - "The Name of Gold" in Christian Science Monitor ( 11 May 1938), p. 7. (Box 5)
        - "White Throated Sparrow in Massachusetts" in Christian Science Monitor ( 16 June 1938), p. 20. (Box 5)
      - Book review, 14 Oct. 1938-22 Apr. 1939; undated; published material (Box 5)
    - We Fly Away
      - Book reviews, 10 Sept. 1948-1 Jan. 1949; undated; published material (Box 5)
  - Essays
    - "Home Forum" in Christian Science Monitor published material
      - 3 Aug. 1938-Oct. 1942, includes correspondence 1942 (Box 6)
      - 1 photo, 6 Jan. 1940 (Box 6)
      - 26 Apr. 1943-15 Dec. 1949, includes correspondence 1943, 1946-1948 (Box 6)
      - 2 photos, 5 Feb. 1947
      - 18 Jan. 1950-25 June 1952, includes correspondence 1950-1952 (Box 6)
      - 31 July 1952-3 Aug. 1954, undated, includes correspondence, 1953 and 3 photos, 1953 and undated (Box 6)
  - Non-fiction
    - "The Muse Not Wholly Serious" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, vol. 42, no. 2 ( Spring, 1966), pp. 272-278. (Box 7)
    - "On Robert Frost" by R. Francis, C.W. Cole, R. L. Cook in The Massachusetts Review, vol. 4, no. 2 ( Winter, 1963) pp. 237-239. (Box 7)
    - "The Satirical Rogue" in The Massachusetts Review, vol. 6 no. 3. ( Spring-Summer, 1965), pp. 151-466. (Box 7)
    - "Ten Below Ezra" in the New England Galaxy, vol. 19, no. 2 ( Fall, 1976), pp. 22-25 (Box 7)
    - "Wild But Polished" in Bits and Several Pieces from the Cranbrook Writing Conference 18-20 Aug. 1967, pp. 9-14. (Box 7)
  - Poetry
    - Worksheets "suitable for publication"
      - "The Base Stealer", [1 Aug. 1947] (Box 7)
      - "Bluejay", [21 Jan. 1956] (Box 7)
      - "Delicate The Toad", [9 Mar. 1962] (Box 7)
      - "Hide-and-Seek", [22 July 1944] (Box 7)
      - "Sniper", [17 Sept. 1960] (Box 7)
      - "Stellaria", undated (Box 7)
  - Worksheets
    - "Aurea Apprehensio", undated (Box 8)
    - "The Bull dozer", 9 July 1960 (Box 8)
    - "Cromwell", 14 Oct. 1966 (Box 8)
    - "Light Casualties", 5 Dec. 1965; holograph (Box 8)
    - "Two Young Women on a Late-Winter Holiday Morning", 22 Feb. 1966 (Box 8)
    - "High Diver", "Swimmer", "Pitcher", "Beyond Biology", "Picasso and Matisse", "Apple Peeler" in New Poems by American Poets, ed. Rolfe Humphries (New York, 1953), pp. 65-67. [vol. 4] (Box 8)
    - "Magazines containing poems not included in my volumes" published material, Aug. 1953-Oct. 1967
      - "The Hawk" in The Malahat Review, no. 4 ( Oct. 1967) p.118. (Box 8)
      - "Late Cricket" in The Lyric, vol. 34, no. 1 ( Winter, 1954), p. 11. (Box 8)
      - "Mr. Eliot's Day" in The New Yorker, vol. 29, no. 24 ( Aug. 1, 1953), p. 27. (Box 8)
      - "The Net" in The Yale Review, vol. 43, no. 4 ( June, 1954), p. 534. (Box 8)